<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="section-135.802">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.802" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.802" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#missouri-legislature" />
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-mo" />
          <akn:FRBRnumber value="135.802" />
          <akn:FRBRname value="Missouri Revised Statutes" />
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.802/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.802/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="eng" />
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
        <akn:FRBRManifestation>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.802/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.802/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
        </akn:FRBRManifestation>
      </akn:identification>
      <akn:references source="#cosilico">
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="missouri-legislature" href="https://revisor.mo.gov" showAs="Missouri General Assembly" />
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico" />
      </akn:references>
      <akn:notes>
        <akn:note eId="source">
          <akn:p>Source: https://revisor.mo.gov/main/OneSection.aspx?section=135.802</akn:p>
        </akn:note>
      </akn:notes>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_135_802">
        <akn:num>135.802</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Section 135.802</akn:heading>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>1.  Beginning January 1, 2005, all applications for all tax credit programs shall include, in addition to any requirements provided by the enacting statutes of a particular credit program, the following information to be submitted to the department administering the tax credit:</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_1__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>Name, address, and phone number of the applicant or applicants, and the name, address, and phone number of a contact person or agent for the applicant or applicants;</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_1__subsec_2">
            <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>Taxpayer type, whether individual, corporation, nonprofit or other, and taxpayer identification number, if applicable;</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_1__subsec_3">
            <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>Standard industry code, if applicable;</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_1__subsec_4">
            <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>Program name and type of tax credit, including the identity of any other state or federal program being utilized for the same activity or project; and</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_1__subsec_5">
            <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>Number of estimated jobs to be directly created, as a result of the tax credits, if applicable, separated by construction, part-time permanent, and full-time permanent.</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>2.  In addition to the information required by subsection 1 of this section, an applicant for a community development tax credit shall also provide information detailing the title and location of the corresponding project, the estimated time period for completion of the project, and all geographic areas impacted by the project.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>3.  In addition to the information required by subsection 1 of this section, an applicant for a redevelopment tax credit shall also provide information detailing the location and legal description of the property, age of the structure, if applicable, whether the property is residential, commercial, or governmental, and the projected project cost, labor cost, and projected date of completion.  Where a redevelopment tax credit applicant is required to submit contemporaneously a federal application for a similar credit on the same underlying project, the submission of a copy of the federal application shall be sufficient to meet the requirements of this subsection.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>4.  In addition to the information required by subsection 1 of this section, an applicant for a business recruitment tax credit shall also provide information detailing the category of business by size, the address of the business headquarters and all offices located within this state, the number of employees at the time of the application, the number of employees projected to increase as a result of the completion of the project, and the estimated project cost.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_5">
          <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_5">
          <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>5.  In addition to the information required by subsection 1 of this section, an applicant for a training and educational tax credit shall also provide information detailing the name and address of the educational institution to be used, the average salary of workers to be served, the estimated project cost, and the number of employees and number of students to be served.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_6">
          <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_6">
          <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>6.  In addition to the information required by subsection 1 of this section, an applicant for a housing tax credit also shall provide information detailing the address, legal description, and fair market value of the property, and the projected labor cost and projected completion date of the project.  Where a housing tax credit applicant is required to submit contemporaneously a federal application for a similar credit on the same underlying project, the submission of a copy of the federal application shall be sufficient to meet the requirements of this subsection.  For the purposes of this subsection,
"fair market value"
means the value as of the purchase of the property or the most recent assessment, whichever is more recent.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_7">
          <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_7">
          <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>7.  In addition to the information required by subsection 1 of this section, an applicant for an entrepreneurial tax credit shall also provide information detailing the amount of investment and the names of the project, fund, and research project.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_8">
          <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_8">
          <akn:num>(8)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>8.  In addition to the information required by subsection 1 of this section, an applicant for an agricultural tax credit shall also provide information detailing the type of agricultural commodity, the amount of contribution, the type of equipment purchased, and the name and description of the facility.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_9">
          <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_9">
          <akn:num>(9)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>9.  In addition to the information required by subsection 1 of this section, an applicant for an environmental tax credit shall also include information detailing the type of equipment, if applicable, purchased and any environmental impact statement, if required by state or federal law.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_10">
          <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_10">
          <akn:num>(10)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>10.  An administering agency, or the department of economic development with the consent of an administering agency, may, by rule, require additional information to be submitted by an applicant.  Any rule or portion of a rule, as that term is defined in section
536.010
, that is created pursuant to the authority delegated in this section shall become effective only if it complies with and is subject to all of the provisions of
chapter 536
and if applicable, section
536.028
.  This section and
chapter 536
are nonseverable and if any of the powers vested with the general assembly pursuant to
chapter 536
to review, to delay the effective date or to disapprove and annul a rule are subsequently held unconstitutional, then the grant of rulemaking authority and any rule proposed or adopted after August 28, 2004, shall be void.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_11">
          <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_11">
          <akn:num>(11)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>11.  Where the sole requirement for receiving a tax credit in the enabling legislation of any tax credit is an obligatory assessment upon a taxpayer or a monetary contribution to a particular group or entity, the application requirements provided in this section shall apply to the recipient of such assessment or contribution and shall not apply to the assessed nor the contributor.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_12">
          <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_802__subsec_12">
          <akn:num>(12)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>12.  It shall be the duty of each administering agency to provide information to every applicant, at some time prior to authorization of an applicant's tax credit application, wherein the requirements of this section, the annual reporting requirements of section
135.805
, and the penalty provisions of section
135.810
are described in detail.  Every applicant for a tax credit under a tax credit program, as part of the application process and as a condition of receiving such tax credit, shall sign a statement affirming that the applicant is aware of the reporting requirements of section
135.805
and the penalty provisions of section
135.810
.
­­--------
(L. 2004 S.B. 1099, A.L. 2009 H.B. 191, A.L. 2022 H.B. 2400)</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
