<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="section-135.1670">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.1670" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.1670" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#missouri-legislature" />
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-mo" />
          <akn:FRBRnumber value="135.1670" />
          <akn:FRBRname value="Missouri Revised Statutes" />
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.1670/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.1670/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="eng" />
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
        <akn:FRBRManifestation>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.1670/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.1670/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
        </akn:FRBRManifestation>
      </akn:identification>
      <akn:references source="#cosilico">
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="missouri-legislature" href="https://revisor.mo.gov" showAs="Missouri General Assembly" />
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico" />
      </akn:references>
      <akn:notes>
        <akn:note eId="source">
          <akn:p>Source: https://revisor.mo.gov/main/OneSection.aspx?section=135.1670</akn:p>
        </akn:note>
      </akn:notes>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_135_1670">
        <akn:num>135.1670</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Section 135.1670</akn:heading>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>1.  As used in this section, the following terms mean:</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_1__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>"Kansas border county"
, Johnson, Miami, or Wyandotte County in Kansas;</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_1__subsec_2">
            <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>"Missouri border county"
, any county with a charter form of government and with more than six hundred thousand but fewer than seven hundred thousand inhabitants, any county of the first classification with more than eighty-three thousand but fewer than ninety-two thousand inhabitants and with a city of the fourth classification with more than four thousand five hundred but fewer than five thousand inhabitants as the county seat, any county of the first classification with more than two hundred thousand but fewer than two hundred sixty thousand inhabitants, or any county of the first classification with more than ninety-two thousand but fewer than one hundred one thousand inhabitants in Missouri.
*</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>2.  If any job that qualifies for a tax credit under sections
100.700 to 100.850
or under sections
135.100 to 135.258
, for funding under section
620.1023
, or for a tax credit or retention of state withholding taxes under sections
620.2000 to 620.2020
, relocates to a Missouri border county from a Kansas border county, no tax credits shall be issued, funding provided, or retention of withholding taxes authorized for such job under such sections.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>3.  If the director of the Missouri department of economic development determines that the state of Kansas has enacted legislation or the governor of Kansas issued an executive order or similar action which prohibits the Kansas Department of Commerce or any other Kansas executive department from providing economic incentives for jobs that are relocated from a Missouri border county to a Kansas border county, then the director shall execute and deliver to the governor, the speaker of the house of representatives, and the president pro tempore of the senate a written certification of such determination.  Upon the execution and delivery of such written certification and the parties receiving such certification providing a unanimous written affirmation, the provisions of subsection 2 of this section shall be effective unless otherwise provided in this section.  The provisions of subsection 2 of this section shall not apply to incentives reserved on behalf of and awarded to Missouri employers prior to the provisions of subsection 2 of this section taking effect.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>4.  If the director of the Missouri department of economic development determines that the Kansas Department of Commerce or any other Kansas executive department is providing economic incentives for jobs that relocate from a Missouri border county to a Kansas border county, then the director shall execute and deliver to the governor, the speaker of the house of representatives, and the president pro tempore of the senate a written certification of such determination.  Upon the execution and delivery of such written certification and the parties receiving such certification providing a unanimous written affirmation, the provisions of subsection 2 of this section shall not be effective until such time as the director determines that the Kansas Department of Commerce or any other Kansas executive department is not providing economic incentives for jobs that relocate from a Missouri border county to a Kansas border county, and the director has executed and delivered to the governor, the speaker of the house of representatives, and the president pro tempore of the senate a written certification of such determination and the parties receiving such certification provide an unanimous written affirmation.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_5">
          <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_5">
          <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>5.  The director of the Missouri department of economic development shall notify the revisor of statutes of all changes in whether subsection 2 of this section is effective.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_6">
          <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_1670__subsec_6">
          <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>6.  The provisions of this section shall expire August 28, 2021, unless at such time the provisions of subsection 2 of this section are in effect.  If the provisions of this section do not expire on August 28, 2021, the provisions of this section shall expire on August 28, 2025.
­­--------
(L. 2014 S.B. 635, A.L. 2019 S.B. 182)
*Effective 11-21-19.  The Revisor was notified by the Department of Economic Development on November 21, 2019, that subsection 2 of this section is effective.
Expires 8-28-25</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
