<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="section-135.279">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.279" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.279" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#missouri-legislature" />
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-mo" />
          <akn:FRBRnumber value="135.279" />
          <akn:FRBRname value="Missouri Revised Statutes" />
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.279/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.279/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="eng" />
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
        <akn:FRBRManifestation>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.279/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.279/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
        </akn:FRBRManifestation>
      </akn:identification>
      <akn:references source="#cosilico">
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="missouri-legislature" href="https://revisor.mo.gov" showAs="Missouri General Assembly" />
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico" />
      </akn:references>
      <akn:notes>
        <akn:note eId="source">
          <akn:p>Source: https://revisor.mo.gov/main/OneSection.aspx?section=135.279</akn:p>
        </akn:note>
      </akn:notes>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_135_279">
        <akn:num>135.279</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Section 135.279</akn:heading>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>1.  Any taxpayer that operates an approved retained business facility in an enterprise zone may be allowed a credit, each year for ten years, in an amount determined pursuant to subsection 2 or 3 of this section, whichever is applicable, against the tax imposed by
chapter 143
, excluding withholding tax imposed by sections
143.191 to 143.265
, as follows:</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_1__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>The credit allowed for each retained business facility employee shall be four hundred dollars, except that for each retained business facility employee that exceeds the level of employment set forth in paragraph</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
            <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_1__subsec_1__subsec_b">
              <akn:num>(b)</akn:num>
              <akn:content>
                <akn:p>of subdivision</akn:p>
              </akn:content>
            </akn:subsection>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_1__subsec_7">
            <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of section
135.276
, the credit shall be five hundred dollars.  Transfers from another facility operated by the taxpayer in the state will not count as retained business facility employees;</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_1__subsec_2">
            <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>An additional credit of four hundred dollars shall be granted for each twelve-month period that a retained business facility employee is a resident of an enterprise zone;</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_1__subsec_3">
            <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>An additional credit of four hundred dollars shall be granted for each twelve-month period that the person employed as a retained business facility employee is a person who, at the time of such employment by the new business facility, met the criteria as set forth in section
135.240
;</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_1__subsec_4">
            <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>To the extent that expenses incurred by a retained business facility in an enterprise zone for the training of persons employed in the operation of the retained business facility is not covered by an existing federal, state, or local program, such retained business facility shall be eligible for a full tax credit equal to eighty percent of that portion of such training expenses which are in excess of four hundred dollars for each trainee who is a resident of an enterprise zone or who was at the time of such employment at the retained business facility unemployable or difficult to employ as defined in section
135.240
, provided such credit shall not exceed four hundred dollars for each employee trained;</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_1__subsec_5">
            <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>The credit allowed for retained business facility investment shall be equal to the sum of ten percent of the first ten thousand dollars of such qualifying investment, plus five percent of the next ninety thousand dollars of such qualifying investment, plus two percent of all remaining qualifying investments within an enterprise zone.  The taxpayer's retained business facility investment shall be reduced by the amount of investment made by the taxpayer or related taxpayer which was subsequently transferred to the retained business facility from another Missouri facility and for which credits authorized in this section are not being earned.</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>2.  The credits allowed by subsection 1 of this section shall offset the greater of:</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_2__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>Some portion of the income tax otherwise imposed by
chapter 143
, excluding withholding tax imposed by sections
143.191 to 143.265
, with respect to such taxpayer's retained business facility income for the taxable year for which such credit is allowed; or</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_2__subsec_2">
            <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>If the taxpayer operates no other facility in Missouri, the credits allowed in subsection 1 of this section shall offset up to fifty percent or, in the case of an economic development project located within a distressed community as defined in section
135.530
, seventy-five percent of the business income tax otherwise imposed by
chapter 143
, excluding withholding tax imposed by sections
143.191 to 143.265
, if the business operates no other facilities in Missouri;</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_2__subsec_3">
            <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>If the taxpayer operates more than one facility in Missouri, the credits allowed in subsection 1 of this section shall offset up to the greater of the portion prescribed in subdivision</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_2__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of this subsection or twenty-five percent or, in the case of an economic development project located within a distressed community as defined in section
135.530
, thirty-five percent of the business' tax, except that no taxpayer operating more than one facility in Missouri shall be allowed to offset more than twenty-five percent or, in the case of an economic development project located within a distressed community as defined in section
135.530
, thirty-five percent of the taxpayer's business income tax in any tax period under the method prescribed in this subdivision.</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>3.  In the case where a person employed by the retained business facility is a resident of the enterprise zone for less than a twelve-month period, or in the case where a person employed as a retained business facility employee is a person who, at the time of such employment by the retained business facility, met the criteria as set forth in section
135.240
, is employed for less than a twelve-month period, the credits allowed by subdivisions</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_3__subsec_2">
            <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>and</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_3__subsec_3">
            <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 1 of this section shall be determined by multiplying the dollar amount of the credit by a fraction, the numerator of which is the number of calendar days during the taxpayer's tax year for which such credits are claimed, in which the person met the requirements prescribed in subdivision</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_3__subsec_2">
            <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>or</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_3__subsec_3">
            <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of this subsection, and the denominator of which is three hundred sixty-five.</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>4.  Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, any taxpayer who claims the exemption and credits allowed in sections
135.276 to 135.283
shall not be eligible to receive the exemption allowed in section
135.220
, the credits allowed in sections
135.225
and
135.235
, and the refund authorized by section
135.245
or the tax credits allowed in section
135.110
.  The taxpayer must elect among the options.  To perfect the election, the taxpayer shall attach written notification of such election to the taxpayer's initial application for claiming tax credits.  The election shall be irreversible once perfected.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_5">
          <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_5">
          <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>5.  A taxpayer shall not receive the income exemption described in section
135.276
and the tax credits described in subsection 1 of this section for any year in which the terms and conditions of sections
135.276 to 135.283
are not met.  Such incentives shall not exceed the fifteen-year limitation pursuant to subsection 1 of section
135.230
or the seven-year limitation pursuant to subsection 5 of section
135.230
.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_6">
          <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_6">
          <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>6.  The initial application for claiming tax credits must be made in the taxpayer's tax period immediately following the tax period in which commencement of commercial operations began at the new business facility.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_7">
          <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_279__subsec_7">
          <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>7.  Credits may not be carried forward but shall be claimed for the taxable year during which continuation of commercial operations occurs at such retained business facility, and for each of the nine succeeding taxable years.
­­--------
(L. 2003 H.B. 289 merged with S.B. 620)
Effective 6-18-03 (S.B. 620); 7-07-03 (H.B. 289)
Contingent expiration date, see § 135.284</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
