<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="section-135.963">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.963" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.963" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#missouri-legislature" />
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-mo" />
          <akn:FRBRnumber value="135.963" />
          <akn:FRBRname value="Missouri Revised Statutes" />
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.963/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.963/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="eng" />
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
        <akn:FRBRManifestation>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.963/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.963/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
        </akn:FRBRManifestation>
      </akn:identification>
      <akn:references source="#cosilico">
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="missouri-legislature" href="https://revisor.mo.gov" showAs="Missouri General Assembly" />
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico" />
      </akn:references>
      <akn:notes>
        <akn:note eId="source">
          <akn:p>Source: https://revisor.mo.gov/main/OneSection.aspx?section=135.963</akn:p>
        </akn:note>
      </akn:notes>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_135_963">
        <akn:num>135.963</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Section 135.963</akn:heading>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>1.  Improvements made to real property as such term is defined in section
137.010
which are made in an enhanced enterprise zone subsequent to the date such zone or expansion thereto was designated may, upon approval of an authorizing resolution or ordinance by the governing authority having jurisdiction of the area in which the improvements are made, be exempt, in whole or in part, from assessment and payment of ad valorem taxes of one or more affected political subdivisions.  Improvements made to real property, as such term is defined in section
137.010
, which are locally assessed and in a renewable energy generation zone designated as an enhanced enterprise zone, subsequent to the date such enhanced enterprise zone or expansion thereto was designated, may, upon approval of an authorizing resolution or ordinance by the governing authority having jurisdiction of the area in which the improvements are made, be exempt, in whole or in part, from assessment and payment of ad valorem taxes of one or more affected political subdivisions.  In addition to enhanced business enterprises, a speculative industrial or warehouse building constructed by a public entity or a private entity if the land is leased by a public entity may be subject to such exemption.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>2.  Such authorizing resolution shall specify the percent of the exemption to be granted, the duration of the exemption to be granted, and the political subdivisions to which such exemption is to apply and any other terms, conditions, or stipulations otherwise required.  A copy of the resolution shall be provided to the director within thirty calendar days following adoption of the resolution by the governing authority.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>3.  No exemption shall be granted until the governing authority holds a public hearing for the purpose of obtaining the opinions and suggestions of residents of political subdivisions to be affected by the exemption from property taxes.  The governing authority shall send, by certified mail, a notice of such hearing to each political subdivision in the area to be affected and shall publish notice of such hearing in a newspaper of general circulation in the area to be affected by the exemption at least twenty days prior to the hearing but not more than thirty days prior to the hearing.  Such notice shall state the time, location, date, and purpose of the hearing.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>4.  Notwithstanding subsection 1 of this section, at least one-half of the ad valorem taxes otherwise imposed on subsequent improvements to real property located in an enhanced enterprise zone of enhanced business enterprises or speculative industrial or warehouse buildings as indicated in subsection 1 of this section shall become and remain exempt from assessment and payment of ad valorem taxes of any political subdivision of this state or municipality thereof, if said political subdivision or municipality levies ad valorem taxes, for a period of not less than ten years following the date such improvements were assessed, provided the improved properties are used for enhanced business enterprises.  The exemption for speculative buildings is subject to the approval of the governing authority for a period not to exceed two years if the building is owned by a private entity and five years if the building is owned or ground leased by a public entity.  This shall not preclude the building receiving an exemption for the remaining time period established by the governing authority if it was occupied by an enhanced business enterprise.  The two- and five-year time periods indicated for speculative buildings shall not be an addition to the local abatement time period for such facility.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_5">
          <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_5">
          <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>5.  No exemption shall be granted for a period more than twenty-five years, provided, however, that during the ten years prior to the expiration of an enhanced enterprise zone no exemption shall be granted for a period of more than ten years.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_6">
          <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_6">
          <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>6.  The provisions of subsection 1 of this section shall not apply to improvements made to real property begun prior to August 28, 2004.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_7">
          <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_7">
          <akn:num>(7)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>7.  The abatement referred to in this section shall not relieve the assessor or other responsible official from ascertaining the amount of the equalized assessed value of all taxable property annually as required by section
99.855
,
99.957
, or
99.1042
and shall not have the effect of reducing the payments in lieu of taxes referred to in subdivision</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_7__subsec_2">
            <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 1 of section
99.845
, subdivision</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_7__subsec_2">
            <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 3 of section
99.957
, or subdivision</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_7__subsec_2">
            <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 3 of section
99.1042
unless such reduction is set forth in the plan approved by the governing body of the municipality pursuant to subdivision</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_963__subsec_7__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 1 of section
99.820
, section
99.942
, or section
99.1027
.
­­--------
(L. 2004 S.B. 1155 § 135.1065, A.L. 2007 1st Ex. Sess. H.B. 1, A.L. 2011 H.B. 737, A.L. 2012 S.B. 769, A.L. 2017 S.B. 111)</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
        </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
