<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="section-135.503">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.503" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.503" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#missouri-legislature" />
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-mo" />
          <akn:FRBRnumber value="135.503" />
          <akn:FRBRname value="Missouri Revised Statutes" />
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.503/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.503/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="eng" />
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
        <akn:FRBRManifestation>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.503/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.503/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
        </akn:FRBRManifestation>
      </akn:identification>
      <akn:references source="#cosilico">
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="missouri-legislature" href="https://revisor.mo.gov" showAs="Missouri General Assembly" />
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico" />
      </akn:references>
      <akn:notes>
        <akn:note eId="source">
          <akn:p>Source: https://revisor.mo.gov/main/OneSection.aspx?section=135.503</akn:p>
        </akn:note>
      </akn:notes>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_135_503">
        <akn:num>135.503</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Section 135.503</akn:heading>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>1.  Any investor that makes an investment of certified capital shall, in the year of investment, earn a vested credit against state premium tax liability equal to the applicable percentage of the investor's investment of certified capital.  An investor shall be entitled to take up to ten percent of the vested credit in any taxable year of the investor.  Any time after three years after August 28, 1996, the director, with the approval of the commissioner of administration, may reduce the applicable percentage on a prospective basis.  Any such reduction in the applicable percentage by the director shall not have any effect on credits against state premium tax liability which have been claimed or will be claimed by any investor with respect to credits which have been earned and vested pursuant to an investment of certified capital prior to the effective date of any such change.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>2.  An insurance company claiming a state premium tax credit earned through an investment in a certified capital company shall not be required to pay any additional retaliatory tax levied pursuant to section
375.916
as a result of claiming such credit.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>3.  The credit against state premium tax liability which is described in subsection 1 of this section may not exceed the state premium tax liability of the investor for any taxable year.  All such credits against state premium tax liability may be carried forward indefinitely until the credits are utilized.  The maximum amount of certified capital in one or more certified capital companies for which earned and vested tax credits will be allowed in any year to any one investor or its affiliates shall be limited to ten million dollars.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>4.  Except as provided in subsection 5 of this section, the aggregate amount of certified capital for which earned and vested credits against state premium tax liability are allowed for all persons pursuant to sections
135.500 to 135.529
shall not exceed the following amounts:  for calendar year 1996, $0.00; for calendar year 1997, an amount which would entitle all Missouri certified capital company investors to take aggregate credits of five million dollars; and for any year thereafter, an additional amount to be determined by the director but not to exceed aggregate credits of ten million dollars for any year with the approval of the commissioner of administration and reported to the general assembly as provided in subsection 2 of section
33.282
, provided that the amount so determined shall not impair the ability of an investor with earned and vested credits which have been allowed in previous years to take them, pursuant to subsection 1 of this section.  During any calendar year in which the limitation described in this subsection will limit the amount of certified capital for which earned and vested credits against state premium tax liability are allowed, certified capital for which credits are allowed will be allocated in order of priority based upon the date of filing of information described in subdivision</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_4__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 5 of section
135.516
.  Certified capital limited in any calendar year by the application of the provisions of this subsection shall be allowed and allocated in the immediately succeeding calendar year in the order of priority set forth in this subsection.  The department shall make separate allocations of certified capital for which credits are allowed under the limitations described in this subsection and under the limitations described in subsection 5 of this section.</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_5">
          <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_5">
          <akn:num>(5)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>5.  In addition to the maximum amount pursuant to subsection 4 of this section, the aggregate amount of certified capital for which earned and vested credits against state premium tax liability are allowed for persons pursuant to sections
135.500 to 135.529
shall be the following:  for calendar year 1999 and for any year thereafter, an amount to be determined by the director which would entitle all Missouri certified capital company investors to take aggregate credits not to exceed four million dollars for any year with the approval of the commissioner of administration and reported to the general assembly as provided in subsection 2 of section
33.282
, provided that the amount so determined shall not impair the ability of an investor with earned and vested credits which have been allowed in previous years or pursuant to the provisions of subsection 4 of this section to take them, pursuant to subsection 1 of this section.  For purposes of any requirement regarding the schedule of qualified investments for certified capital for which earned and vested credits against state premium tax liability are allowed pursuant to this subsection only, the definition of a
"qualified Missouri business"
as set forth in subdivision</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_5__subsec_14">
            <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 2 of section
135.500
means a Missouri business that is located in a distressed community as defined in section
135.530
, and meets all of the requirements of subdivision</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_5__subsec_14">
            <akn:num>(14)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 2 of section
135.500
.  During any calendar year in which the limitation described in this subsection limits the amount of additional certified capital for which earned and vested credits against state premium tax liability are allowed, additional certified capital for which credits are allowed shall be allocated in order of priority based upon the date of filing of information described in subdivision</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_5__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 5 of section
135.516
with respect to such additional certified capital. The department shall make separate allocations of certified capital for which credits are allowed under the limitations described in this subsection and under the limitations described in subsection 4 of this section.  No limitation applicable to any certified capital company with respect to certified capital for which credits are allowed pursuant to subsection 4 of this section shall limit the amount of certified capital for which credits are allowed pursuant to this subsection.  No limitation applicable to any certified capital company with respect to certified capital for which credits are allowed pursuant to this subsection shall limit the amount of certified capital for which credits are allowed pursuant to subsection 4 of this section.</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_6">
          <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_6">
          <akn:num>(6)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>6.  The department shall advise any Missouri certified capital company, in writing, within fifteen days after receiving the filing described in subdivision</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_503__subsec_6__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 5 of section
135.516
whether the limitations of subsection 3 of this section then in effect will be applicable with respect to the investments and credits described in such filing with the department.
­­--------
(L. 1996 H.B. 1237, A.L. 1997 2d Ex. Sess. S.B. 1, A.L. 1998 H.B. 1656, A.L. 2003 H.B. 289)
CROSS REFERENCE:
Tax Credit Accountability Act of 2004, additional requirements, 135.800 to 135.830</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
        </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
