<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<akn:akomaNtoso xmlns:akn="http://docs.oasis-open.org/legaldocml/ns/akn/3.0">
  <akn:act name="section-135.247">
    <akn:meta>
      <akn:identification source="#cosilico">
        <akn:FRBRWork>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.247" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.247" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#missouri-legislature" />
          <akn:FRBRcountry value="us-mo" />
          <akn:FRBRnumber value="135.247" />
          <akn:FRBRname value="Missouri Revised Statutes" />
        </akn:FRBRWork>
        <akn:FRBRExpression>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.247/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.247/eng@2025-12-31" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
          <akn:FRBRlanguage language="eng" />
        </akn:FRBRExpression>
        <akn:FRBRManifestation>
          <akn:FRBRthis value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.247/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRuri value="/akn/us-mo/act/mrs/section-135.247/eng@2025-12-31/main" />
          <akn:FRBRdate date="2025-12-31" name="generation" />
          <akn:FRBRauthor href="#cosilico" />
        </akn:FRBRManifestation>
      </akn:identification>
      <akn:references source="#cosilico">
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="missouri-legislature" href="https://revisor.mo.gov" showAs="Missouri General Assembly" />
        <akn:TLCOrganization eId="cosilico" href="https://cosilico.ai" showAs="Cosilico" />
      </akn:references>
      <akn:notes>
        <akn:note eId="source">
          <akn:p>Source: https://revisor.mo.gov/main/OneSection.aspx?section=135.247</akn:p>
        </akn:note>
      </akn:notes>
    </akn:meta>
    <akn:body>
      <akn:section eId="sec_135_247">
        <akn:num>135.247</akn:num>
        <akn:heading>Section 135.247</akn:heading>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_1">
          <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>1.  Notwithstanding the provisions of sections
135.205
,
135.207
, and
135.210
or any other provisions to the contrary, any area having been designated by the United States Department of Housing and Urban Development as a federal empowerment zone or by the United States Department of Agriculture as an enterprise community pursuant to the federal Omnibus Budget Reconciliation Act of 1993, title XIII, chapter I, subchapter c, shall immediately upon such federal designation become and remain a state enterprise zone until the expiration of such federal designation.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_2">
          <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>2.  The credits otherwise provided by sections
135.225
and
135.235
, the exemption provided by section
135.220
, and the refund provided by section
135.245
shall be available to any taxpayer who establishes and operates a new business facility located within a federal empowerment zone or enterprise community on the same terms and conditions specified in sections
135.100 to 135.256
.  The exemption provided in section
135.215
shall be available to any taxpayer who makes improvements to real property after the date the area is designated as a federal empowerment zone or enterprise community pursuant to the same terms and conditions specified in section
135.215
.</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_3">
          <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>3.  Notwithstanding any provision of law to the contrary, retail businesses, as defined by SICs 52 through 59, hotels and motels, as defined by SIC 7011, and recreational facilities as defined by SIC 7999, shall be eligible for all benefits provided pursuant to the provisions of sections
135.200 to 135.256
, if:</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_3__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>In the case of a retail business, such business is located within a state-designated enterprise zone located wholly or partially within a federal empowerment zone or enterprise community; or</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_3__subsec_2">
            <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>Such business is located within a satellite enterprise zone, established pursuant to subdivision</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_3__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>or</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_3__subsec_3">
            <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 1 of section
135.207
, whether or not such satellite zone is contained within a federal empowerment zone or enterprise community; and</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_3__subsec_3">
            <akn:num>(3)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>In the case of a hotel or motel, such business is located within an enterprise zone which is located within any county of the first classification with a population of at least five hundred thousand but less than seven hundred thousand inhabitants according to the last decennial census, or in an enterprise zone which is located within any city of the third classification which is partially located within a county of the first class with a population of one hundred fifty thousand or more which is adjacent to a county of the first classification with a population of at least five hundred thousand but less than seven hundred thousand according to the last decennial census; and</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_3__subsec_4">
            <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>In the case of a recreational facility, such business is located within an area designated a satellite enterprise zone pursuant to subdivision</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_3__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>of subsection 1 of section
135.207
, by the director after January 1, 1991, and before January 1, 1992, in any city not within a county, and further provided the director approves the eligibility of such recreational facility to claim tax benefits otherwise allowed in sections
135.200 to 135.256
.  When making such determination, the director shall consider the number and quality of new jobs to be created, the amount of payroll and investment to be generated from the proposed project, the extent to which such tax concessions are needed to induce the development, whether the area is unlikely to support reasonable tax assessment or to experience reasonable economic growth without such designation and the overall economic benefits to be realized from the proposed project.</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
        </akn:subsection>
        <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_4">
          <akn:num>(4)</akn:num>
          <akn:content>
            <akn:p>4.  For purposes of qualifying for benefits pursuant to this section, recreational facilities, as defined by SIC 7999, shall not include:</akn:p>
          </akn:content>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_4__subsec_1">
            <akn:num>(1)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>An excursion gambling boat licensed pursuant to sections
313.800 to 313.850
and the docking facility associated with such licensed excursion gambling boat; or</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
          <akn:subsection eId="sec_135_247__subsec_4__subsec_2">
            <akn:num>(2)</akn:num>
            <akn:content>
              <akn:p>An excursion gambling boat and docking facility as proposed on an application filed with the Missouri gaming commission.
­­--------
(L. 1994 H.B. 1248 &amp; 1048, A.L. 1995 H.B. 414, A.L. 1996 H.B. 1237, A.L. 1997 2d Ex. Sess. S.B. 1)
Effective 12-23-97</akn:p>
            </akn:content>
          </akn:subsection>
        </akn:subsection>
      </akn:section>
    </akn:body>
  </akn:act>
</akn:akomaNtoso>
